<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brainbaking.com/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>De zin en onzin van conferenties</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/de-zin-en-onzin-van-conferenties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/de-zin-en-onzin-van-conferenties/</guid>
      <description>Bedrijven zien conferenties vaak als een onnodige kost waar hun werknemers nauwelijks worden naar toe gestuurd. Meestal gaat dit keurig af van het jaarlijks opleidingsbudget, ook weer keurig verrekend en verdeeld per persoon. Als Piet graag drie dagen wenst te gaan, en Jan in hetzelfde team ook, ontstaat er al een probleem: wie gaat dan die grote hoeveelheid dagelijkse problemen opkuisen? Er wordt een compromis gesloten: Piet en Jan mogen elk slechts één dag gaan, en elk op één aparte dag van het evenement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over analoog en digitaal</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-analoog-en-digitaal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-analoog-en-digitaal/</guid>
      <description>Eens blazen en hem &amp;ldquo;er uit en weer in steken&amp;rdquo; - aan wat doet deze vreemde uitspraak denken? Zedige kinderen die opgroeiden in de jaren &amp;lsquo;90 denken hopelijk onmiddellijk aan een console cartridge: slecht contact met de console zelf door mogelijke stofjes zorgde er voor dat je console spel niet goed opstartte. De gebruikelijke handeling om het ding terug draaiende te krijgen was de cartridge uit de console trekken, eens goed op de contacten &amp;ldquo;blazen&amp;rdquo;, en hem er goed terug in drukken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boeken die mij gevormd hebben tot wie ik ben</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/boeken-die-mij-gevormd-hebben/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/boeken-die-mij-gevormd-hebben/</guid>
      <description>Zoals 2017 in boeken kan worden uitgedrukt, zo kan mijn leven in zijn geheel tot nu toe worden uitgedrukt in de boeken die het sterk beïnvloed heeft. Tijdens het lezen van Montaigne&amp;rsquo;s Essays kwam ik tot de vaststelling dat ook Michel de onderwerpen van zijn &amp;lsquo;Essais&amp;rsquo; laat afhangen van de voorgaande werken die hij onder ogen heeft gekregen, zoals Cicero en Seneca in deel I. Iedereen moet immers zijn inspiratie ergens vandaan halen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over de inflatie van intellect</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-intellect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-intellect/</guid>
      <description>Het resultaat van een onderzoek dat ik las in Frank Furedi&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Waar zijn de intellectuelen?&amp;rdquo; boezemt mij veel angst in: minder dan de helft van de samenleving wil tegenwoordig nog literatuur lezen. En dit gaat dan nog over literatuur! Ik ken veel mensen die met hun ogen draaien zodra ik nog maar het woord &amp;ldquo;boek&amp;rdquo; uitspreek, laat staan een conversatie over filosofie aan te gaan. Ik had er niet bij stilgestaan dat dit eenvoudig geëxtrapoleerd kan worden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over tijdsbesef</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-tijdsbesef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-tijdsbesef/</guid>
      <description>In Venteuil, een klein dorpje in de Champagne streek te Frankrijk dat vijfhonderd hele inwoners telt, ligt wijnmaker Autréau-Lasnot. Er zijn honderden grote en kleine champagneboeren gevestigd in de streek - overal waar je kijkt zie je wijnstokken vergezeld met rozen en bijenkorven. Ik drink geen alcohol, maar dat is geen reden om een uitgebreid bezoek af te slaan: ik hou van alles wat met fermentatie te maken heeft. Het alcoholisch bijproduct is dan voor mij natuurlijk jammer: terwijl iedereen zich bezat aan de verschillende proeverijen kan ik vrolijk wat rondkijken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over het introduceren van bedrijfsethiek</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-bedrijfsethiek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-bedrijfsethiek/</guid>
      <description>Addendum: 7 highly successful software engineering cultures is de moeite om in detail na te lezen, waarbij bedrijven zoals GitLab hun &amp;ldquo;Team Handboek&amp;rdquo; open stellen. Het gaat véél verder dan enkel een cultuur: er staat in wanneer aandeelhouders samenkomen, hoe er omgegaan wordt met nieuwe kandidaten en hoe je je verlof dient in te plannen. Transparantie zò sterk door de aorta van het bedrijf laten stromen, is zeer bewonderenswaardig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over entropie</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-entropie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/over-entropie/</guid>
      <description>Filosofie kan gezien worden als een poging om dingen rondom de mensheid te definiëren. Ik noem het een poging, en geen manier, omdat we al duizenden jaren kritiek aan het geven zijn op elkaars definities. Ik noem het dingen, en niet zichtbare dingen, omdat juist ongrijpbare dingen ons zo sterk intrigeren dat we ook de nood voelen om daar een theoretische vorm aan te koppelen.
Ons bewustzijn produceert veel prachtige wetenschapstakken maar ook veel angsten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concentrating on serendipitous creativity</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/serendipitous-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/serendipitous-creativity/</guid>
      <description>When was the last time you were able to focus well on a difficult task in an office landscape? For long periods of time? Did you manage to finish the task in time? Knowledge workers are increasingly pushed together in large open spaces to promote collaboration and serendipity. But those unplanned happy accidents create another completely unplanned rather unhappy accident: the loss of concentration. According to Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Deep Work&amp;rdquo; term, long uninterrupted hours of concentration manage to get difficult things done - not short bursts of collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take your time.</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/take-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/take-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to keep silent for a minute and enjoy the complete absence of traffic noise!&amp;rdquo; I yelled to my friends. We were standing on a sandy hill in the middle of national park &amp;ldquo;Hoge Veluwe&amp;rdquo;. One of our friends, a biologist, enticed us to help him identify animal tracks in the sand. I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about even-toed ungulates, but I know a bit about the joy of discovery.  &amp;ldquo;Great idea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 in books</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/2017-in-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/2017-in-books/</guid>
      <description>Goodreads presented me with a neat overview on my read books in 2017 you can also take a look at. The dull page statistics are of no interest to me, but the kind of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read do tell a story that might be worth sharing.
When it comes to keeping track of what I read, Goodreads might be the best thing that happened to me yet. But I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I&amp;rsquo;m a consequent user of my own listage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventing - for the worse?</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/inventing-for-the-worse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/inventing-for-the-worse/</guid>
      <description>People have an irresistible urge to create. But we often mistake productivity with creativity with really creating. Homo creativus. But is this always a good thing? The best inventions in the world bring great sorrow to millions of people today. Then I started wondering, what if&amp;hellip;
Electricity wasn&amp;rsquo;t invented? Mass production wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible. Everything you use, from your watch to your laptop, stove, to what you&amp;rsquo;re wearing wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m jealous of my dog</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/i-am-jealous-of-my-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/i-am-jealous-of-my-dog/</guid>
      <description>My dog, Miel (yes, like the French word for honey. It&amp;rsquo;s a Golden Retriever, get the link?), loves to walk. He also likes playing a lot, but as soon as I put on my shoes or get near the garden gate, he starts to freak out, thinking it&amp;rsquo;s that time again. Since I have no idea what is going on in is head, I said &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo;, because we humans associate animals with our own behavior - because that&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re familiar with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journaling in practice</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/journaling-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/journaling-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why you should journal in the first place, then maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to start reading here and here.
There are hundreds of resources available on the Internet on how to journal, how to keep a bullet journal, how to index everything, how to getting things done and so forth. The following advice is something that works for me - it might not work for you at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuts about local nuts</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/nuts-about-local-nuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/nuts-about-local-nuts/</guid>
      <description>Remembering David Lebovitz&amp;rsquo; pine nut syndrome, I started to take a closer look at packages of food we buy at the local supermarket. It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to get completely focused on buying local vegetables but forgetting to look at the label when throwing something like pine nuts into the shopping cart. The worst thing is, most supermarkets don&amp;rsquo;t care and don&amp;rsquo;t offer an alternative. However, let&amp;rsquo;s not panic just yet: this is slowly changing (but reached a plateau).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing creative scars</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</guid>
      <description>Want to skip to the practical part?
Are you aware of your problems? Once upon a time in a land not very far away (in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the very same we live in), a small boy and his Gameboy grew up. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many hobbies: gaming. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends. Playing outside is okay as long as the 4 AA batteries are fully charged and the sun isn&amp;rsquo;t shining too bright and the playing is confined to one square meter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A samurai learning mindset</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/a-samurai-learning-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/a-samurai-learning-mindset/</guid>
      <description>After reading the famed books The Book of five rings By Miyamoto Musashi and the Life-giving sword By Yagyu Munenori, I started making connections between the teachings of the art of war and the teachings of any other craft. Yagyu clearly mentions the state of mind required to survive in battle can be used in any other profession to your advantage as well.
The back of the book states that &amp;ldquo;every manager, seeker of life wisdom and practician of martial arts should use this&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you handing over enough when inspiring someone?</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/handing-over-enough-when-inspiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/handing-over-enough-when-inspiring/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I was having a discussion with a friend and colleague about reaching out to others. He had an idea on combining patterns learned from the enterprise software development world (clean code, TDD, domain driven design, you name it) with patterns learned from the gaming development world (rapid prototyping, getting stuff done, intensive usage of frameworks like Unity). An excellent idea if you ask me. But he was hesitant - others might not be that interested in taking time to write unit tests in their game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching yourself to draw</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/teaching-yourself-to-draw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/teaching-yourself-to-draw/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Noah Bradley&amp;rsquo;s Don&amp;rsquo;t go to art school blog at Medium.com.
Drawing and art in general has always been something I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite grasp or try to understand. I was a software development guy, a technical guy, used to writing code, looking at text, spending days and years in text editors others call IDE&amp;rsquo;s. Software development and art aren&amp;rsquo;t that different actually: they both require an open mindset and an extreme creative approach at solving problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to become a baker</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/learning-to-become-a-baker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/learning-to-become-a-baker/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
Addendum Red Zuurdesem, my website about baking with sourdough, has been active since 2012, and still is. I hold a professional bread baker&amp;rsquo;s degree since 2016 - this article was written during the first year when I enrolled in the course.
 Sometimes people tell me I’m obsessed with bread. That’s not entirely my fault. (I like to blame others, who doesn’t?) When I was little, my father always baked our own bread on sunday, every single sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No, vegetarians do not eat fish!</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/no-vegetarians-do-not-eat-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/no-vegetarians-do-not-eat-fish/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
The amateurs  “So, you do eat a juicy peace of grilled salmon, right?” “No, I already told you, I’m a vegetarian.” (sigh) Frowning. You can almost hear them thinking “that’s what I meant”. “If you’re a pescatarian, you eat seafood but not other animals”. “Oh, right right, sorry!”.
 It must have been the fourth conversation with somebody, where I have to explain what “being a vegetarian” actually means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On finding your inner zen in big cities</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/on-finding-your-inner-zen-in-big-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/on-finding-your-inner-zen-in-big-cities/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
There have been a lot of love letters to big cities here on Medium recently. I never really understood the love for those busy places, but that should not be a big surprise as we grew up in a relatively small village in Belgium. Our country must be one of the smallest in the world — you can drive from one edge to the other in less than 2 hours (excluding traffic jams of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending your day with happy thoughts</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/can-i-haz-happy-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/can-i-haz-happy-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Past new year, I stopped promising silly things to myself. “This year, I’ll for sure go jogging several times a week!” — or “This year, I’ll really get into learning another language!”. We all know how these things go. Not that I made something up on the very day, these ideas are usually carefully crafted in my sketchbook and are lingering there to be exposed and finally executed.  Originally posted on Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>