<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agile on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>https://brainbaking.com/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agile on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Five reasons why agile and academia don&#39;t go together</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/agile-academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/agile-academia/</guid>
      <description>I wish the word &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo; in the title of this post could go away, but after years of trying, I have to say it cannot. There are so many aspects of the academic world that speak against agility that I had to make the conscious choice to reduce the list to five big reasons why I think both do not converge well. Remember that this is my own subjective opinion, and perhaps also meant to utter some well-meant critique, but by no means a one-sided rant: I have spent rather large parts of my career on both sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Startup of a Lean Doctorate</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/lean-doctorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/lean-doctorate/</guid>
      <description>At the start of my doctoral study, things are a bit woozy. The use of that word &amp;ldquo;bit&amp;rdquo; may be the inverse of exaggeration: shaping an abstract idea into a malleable and well-defined project is a process that can easily take up months. After that you still have to &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo; actually doing stuff in context of your invented project! Most doctorates are classical examples of a waterfall process: come up with an abstract, do your (and a lot of) literature study, reach certain milestones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>