<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Improvement on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Improvement on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Take your time.</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/take-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/take-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to keep silent for a minute and enjoy the complete absence of traffic noise!&amp;rdquo; I yelled to my friends. We were standing on a sandy hill in the middle of national park &amp;ldquo;Hoge Veluwe&amp;rdquo;. One of our friends, a biologist, enticed us to help him identify animal tracks in the sand. I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about even-toed ungulates, but I know a bit about the joy of discovery.  &amp;ldquo;Great idea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventing - for the worse?</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/inventing-for-the-worse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/inventing-for-the-worse/</guid>
      <description>People have an irresistible urge to create. But we often mistake productivity with creativity with really creating. Homo creativus. But is this always a good thing? The best inventions in the world bring great sorrow to millions of people today. Then I started wondering, what if&amp;hellip;
Electricity wasn&amp;rsquo;t invented? Mass production wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible. Everything you use, from your watch to your laptop, stove, to what you&amp;rsquo;re wearing wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/noise/</guid>
      <description>The meanwhile common problem of noise in your head has not been solved just yet. In fact, it has only gotten worse. A lot worse. The garbage thinking problem spread like a disease, clinging onto everything in it&amp;rsquo;s way inside me. It has reached my ears and my mind. I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a distinction between &amp;ldquo;head&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;mind&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;head&amp;rdquo; might be a temporary problem, getting something to stick in your &amp;ldquo;mind&amp;rdquo; sounds a lot more definitive to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m jealous of my dog</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/i-am-jealous-of-my-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/i-am-jealous-of-my-dog/</guid>
      <description>My dog, Miel (yes, like the French word for honey. It&amp;rsquo;s a Golden Retriever, get the link?), loves to walk. He also likes playing a lot, but as soon as I put on my shoes or get near the garden gate, he starts to freak out, thinking it&amp;rsquo;s that time again. Since I have no idea what is going on in is head, I said &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo;, because we humans associate animals with our own behavior - because that&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re familiar with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journaling in practice</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/journaling-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/journaling-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why you should journal in the first place, then maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to start reading here and here.
There are hundreds of resources available on the Internet on how to journal, how to keep a bullet journal, how to index everything, how to getting things done and so forth. The following advice is something that works for me - it might not work for you at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing creative scars</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</guid>
      <description>Want to skip to the practical part?
Are you aware of your problems? Once upon a time in a land not very far away (in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the very same we live in), a small boy and his Gameboy grew up. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many hobbies: gaming. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends. Playing outside is okay as long as the 4 AA batteries are fully charged and the sun isn&amp;rsquo;t shining too bright and the playing is confined to one square meter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A samurai learning mindset</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/a-samurai-learning-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/a-samurai-learning-mindset/</guid>
      <description>After reading the famed books The Book of five rings By Miyamoto Musashi and the Life-giving sword By Yagyu Munenori, I started making connections between the teachings of the art of war and the teachings of any other craft. Yagyu clearly mentions the state of mind required to survive in battle can be used in any other profession to your advantage as well.
The back of the book states that &amp;ldquo;every manager, seeker of life wisdom and practician of martial arts should use this&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending your day with happy thoughts</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/can-i-haz-happy-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/can-i-haz-happy-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Past new year, I stopped promising silly things to myself. “This year, I’ll for sure go jogging several times a week!” — or “This year, I’ll really get into learning another language!”. We all know how these things go. Not that I made something up on the very day, these ideas are usually carefully crafted in my sketchbook and are lingering there to be exposed and finally executed.  Originally posted on Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>