<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing creative scars</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</guid>
      <description>Want to skip to the practical part?
Are you aware of your problems? Once upon a time in a land not very far away (in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the very same we live in), a small boy and his Gameboy grew up. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many hobbies: gaming. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends. Playing outside is okay as long as the 4 AA batteries are fully charged and the sun isn&amp;rsquo;t shining too bright and the playing is confined to one square meter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A samurai learning mindset</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/a-samurai-learning-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/a-samurai-learning-mindset/</guid>
      <description>After reading the famed books The Book of five rings By Miyamoto Musashi and the Life-giving sword By Yagyu Munenori, I started making connections between the teachings of the art of war and the teachings of any other craft. Yagyu clearly mentions the state of mind required to survive in battle can be used in any other profession to your advantage as well.
The back of the book states that &amp;ldquo;every manager, seeker of life wisdom and practician of martial arts should use this&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to become a baker</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/learning-to-become-a-baker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/learning-to-become-a-baker/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
Sometimes people tell me I’m obsessed with bread. That’s not entirely my fault. (I like to blame others, who doesn’t?) When I was little, my father always baked our own bread on sunday, every single sunday. I can’t remember anytime we actually bought bread, except on vacation. At a young age I had no idea how creating something out of nothing actually worked, but I knew it was intriguing — the addition of yeast which caused the dough to bubble up within a short period of time, wow!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On finding your inner zen in big cities</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/on-finding-your-inner-zen-in-big-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/on-finding-your-inner-zen-in-big-cities/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
There have been a lot of love letters to big cities here on Medium recently. I never really understood the love for those busy places, but that should not be a big surprise as we grew up in a relatively small village in Belgium. Our country must be one of the smallest in the world — you can drive from one edge to the other in less than 2 hours (excluding traffic jams of course).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>