<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Braindump on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>https://brainbaking.com/tags/braindump/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Braindump on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/braindump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decade in the Software Engineering industry</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/a-decade-in-the-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/a-decade-in-the-industry/</guid>
      <description>It never occurred to me that an article like this might be very informative for those interested in knowing how things work in the software engineering industry. Google&amp;rsquo;s related results to &amp;ldquo;10 years in IT industry&amp;rdquo; are rather depressing: &amp;ldquo;what to do after 10 years of experience&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;career options after 10 years&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;how to survive industry after 10 years&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;best career path after 10 years&amp;rdquo;. It seems to suggest you&amp;rsquo;re done after &amp;ldquo;grinding to level 10&amp;rdquo; - time to boot up another character build?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you handing over enough when inspiring someone?</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/handing-over-enough-when-inspiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/handing-over-enough-when-inspiring/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I was having a discussion with a friend and colleague about reaching out to others. He had an idea on combining patterns learned from the enterprise software development world (clean code, TDD, domain driven design, you name it) with patterns learned from the gaming development world (rapid prototyping, getting stuff done, intensive usage of frameworks like Unity). An excellent idea if you ask me. But he was hesitant - others might not be that interested in taking time to write unit tests in their game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to become a baker</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/learning-to-become-a-baker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/learning-to-become-a-baker/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
Addendum Red Zuurdesem, my website about baking with sourdough, has been active since 2012, and still is. I hold a professional bread baker&amp;rsquo;s degree since 2016 - this article was written during the first year when I enrolled in the course.
 Sometimes people tell me I’m obsessed with bread. That’s not entirely my fault. (I like to blame others, who doesn’t?) When I was little, my father always baked our own bread on sunday, every single sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No, vegetarians do not eat fish!</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/no-vegetarians-do-not-eat-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/no-vegetarians-do-not-eat-fish/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
The amateurs  “So, you do eat a juicy peace of grilled salmon, right?” “No, I already told you, I’m a vegetarian.” (sigh) Frowning. You can almost hear them thinking “that’s what I meant”. “If you’re a pescatarian, you eat seafood but not other animals”. “Oh, right right, sorry!”.
 It must have been the fourth conversation with somebody, where I have to explain what “being a vegetarian” actually means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On finding your inner zen in big cities</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/on-finding-your-inner-zen-in-big-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/on-finding-your-inner-zen-in-big-cities/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
There have been a lot of love letters to big cities here on Medium recently. I never really understood the love for those busy places, but that should not be a big surprise as we grew up in a relatively small village in Belgium. Our country must be one of the smallest in the world — you can drive from one edge to the other in less than 2 hours (excluding traffic jams of course).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>