<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/teaching/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you handing over enough when inspiring someone?</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/handing-over-enough-when-inspiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/handing-over-enough-when-inspiring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was having a discussion with a friend and colleague about reaching out to others. He had an idea on combining patterns learned from the enterprise software development world (clean code, TDD, domain driven design, you name it) with patterns learned from the gaming development world (rapid prototyping, getting stuff done, intensive usage of frameworks like Unity). An excellent idea if you ask me. But he was hesitant - others might not be that interested in taking time to write unit tests in their game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s called an assumption. So I proposed to write small blog posts in &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; using Markdown and GitHub pages. Very lightweight, only one command away from generating concise entries. This might take 10 minutes of your time per week.
So he nodded. &amp;ldquo;Hm-hmm&amp;rdquo;. And we started talking about something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point I had two choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interrupt the conversation and push further.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore it for now and take a mental note do do something with it later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often enough I&amp;rsquo;ve hit a brick wall with option one. It&amp;rsquo;s annoying for the other person to constantly be interrupted and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make myself very popular. I do have that nasty habit and I&amp;rsquo;m working on that.
But let&amp;rsquo;s return to option two for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forgot about the discussion and moved on.
But taking mental notes is like async AJAX calls: they do return, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know when. That&amp;rsquo;s when it hit me: why don&amp;rsquo;t I email him some details on how to quickly start a blog? Would that be appropriate or not? In any case he&amp;rsquo;s free to delete the email - no harm done. But if he decides to do something with it, all the better. The step from no blog and no experience in Hugo is smaller when a friendly push in the right direction has been given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.brainbaking.com/img/sharing.png&#34; alt=&#34;giving&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could say &amp;ldquo;what have you to gain? Why do you care?&amp;rdquo; And I don&amp;rsquo;t - I&amp;rsquo;m not a game developer, but I do care - a bit - about the subject. I do care - a lot - about my friend and his personal growth. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brainbaking.com/post/teaching-kids-how-to-program/&#34;&gt;Show your work&lt;/a&gt;, remember?
I love to inspire others on things that I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about myself. And sharing is caring. I would love to receive an email with loose ends like this from someone I talked to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my decision to throw some info over the wall has been made. I&amp;rsquo;m eager to find out if the seed has been planted and nurtured. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to see. I will not be disappointed if it has not - giving and expecting something in return is not giving. I love giving. Altruism must have originated from the egocentric self, some believe. I would not count myself to be part of that group.
The Japanese encounter a lot of stress if they are given a gift: it has to be matched in value to give something back which has the same value: not less (shame) or more. It&amp;rsquo;s like trying to buy presents for your family at Christmas: a sometimes horrifying experience. You do not know the value of the gift you&amp;rsquo;ll be given and you&amp;rsquo;ll have to guess how much to spend to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, handing out information - which should be free in the first place - is not the same as handing out something physical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rd.com/true-stories/inspiring/5-stories-that-celebrate-the-spirit-of-giving/&#34;&gt;True giving&lt;/a&gt; is expecting nothing in return.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themindfulword.org/2014/joy-of-giving/&#34;&gt;True giving&lt;/a&gt; is wanting nothing in return!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to teach kids to program</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/teaching-kids-how-to-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/post/teaching-kids-how-to-program/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Jessica Ellis gave a lot of great tips on how to teach kids to program at &lt;a href=&#34;https://techorama2017.sched.com/event/9M8g/the-skills-gap-how-to-inspire-our-kids-to-study-computer-science?iframe=no&amp;amp;w=100%&amp;amp;sidebar=yes&amp;amp;bg=no&#34;&gt;Techorama 2017&lt;/a&gt; in Antwerp. She has ben an active teacher in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tkplabs.org&#34;&gt;tkplabs.org&lt;/a&gt; society and introduced something clever called &amp;ldquo;barbecoding&amp;rdquo;. In an attempt to create an appealing programming camp for boys and girls, she successfully combined food and science. She shared her story in an hour and I did my best to extract the most important principles as I thought it might be a great idea to apply that to our team in my daily work as a software developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would those principles only apply to kids?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-do-hard-things-and-have-food&#34;&gt;1. Do Hard Things (and have food)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t treat people as you categorize them. Do hard things, even if you think they are not capable of doing something like that. Don&amp;rsquo;t label them as &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; - the brain will become wired for failure and they&amp;rsquo;ll be scared to make mistakes.
The food part is especially interesting as I&amp;rsquo;ve read in some management book years ago one concept called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;do food&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Bring (home made) food to a meeting - it immediately breaks all ice, effectively. Since then, I constantly rely on homemade cakecups to ease other&amp;rsquo;s minds. It really does work and it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-work-in-a-group-failing-in-a-group-failing-alone&#34;&gt;2 Work in a group (failing in a group &amp;gt; failing alone)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing and mob programming can be done with kids and enables them to learn faster (from each other instead of only from the teacher or themselves). It&amp;rsquo;s also less bad to try and fail: at least you&amp;rsquo;ve failed together then.
I successfully used mob programming as a teaching instrument at work. It makes the problem less daunting for someone who isn&amp;rsquo;t eager to speak for a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-be-surprised-laugh-a-lot&#34;&gt;3 Be Surprised (laugh a lot)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is full of surprises. Be genuine.
Stop taking everythig seriously. Something I love to do: inspire others to laugh more - at themselves, at me, at the situation we&amp;rsquo;re in. And then get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-feel-powerful-never-say-you-can-t-do-anything&#34;&gt;4. Feel Powerful (never say you can&amp;rsquo;t do anything)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is extremely difficult for grownups and I still can&amp;rsquo;t wrap my head around the why. &amp;ldquo;Oh but I can&amp;rsquo;t do it as good as you&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;you are the expert, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to do such a thing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;no, I can&amp;rsquo;t do that, I&amp;rsquo;m not smart enough&amp;rdquo; are sentences I hear on the workfloor every single day. And that&amp;rsquo;s very very saddening because I&amp;rsquo;m not smarter than anyone else - in fact, I&amp;rsquo;m convinced I know less than they do - I just manage to get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing talent and mentoring them to become teachers themselves is something I have to do more often - that means less work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-show-your-work&#34;&gt;5. Show Your Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reminded me of Austin Kleon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://austinkleon.com/show-your-work/&#34;&gt;show your work&lt;/a&gt; - a lovely book that inspires to put stuff out there, like this very blog or my &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; drawings. I love to show my work, but grownups tend to think someone shows their work because he or she wants everyone to know how great they are.
Maybe. But foremost, they might want feedback. And get better. And that means, they need your help. So stop that train of negative thinking and start helping. Stop saying &amp;ldquo;my work is redundant, it&amp;rsquo;s nothing, it&amp;rsquo;s not showable, nobody would like it&amp;rdquo; and start putting stuff out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-unplug-learn-without-a-computer&#34;&gt;6. Unplug &amp;amp; learn without a computer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computational thinking can also be learned with the help of post-its, some yarn, a thread and some markers. Your cognitive process picks up things a lot faster if your body is &lt;strong&gt;doing stuff&lt;/strong&gt; instead of yawning at a computer screen. Get up and move. Pair more strictly: set a timer and require everyone to physically move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very inspiring to see what Jessica and her team of teachers (15 year olds by the way!) managed to do. I know I&amp;rsquo;ll be trying to incorporate the rules stated above in my daily work, even if I&amp;rsquo;m not directly working with kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I am&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>