<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journaling on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>https://brainbaking.com/tags/journaling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journaling on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/journaling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boeken die mij gevormd hebben tot wie ik ben</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/essays/boeken-die-mij-gevormd-hebben/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/essays/boeken-die-mij-gevormd-hebben/</guid>
      <description>Zoals 2017 in boeken kan worden uitgedrukt, zo kan mijn leven in zijn geheel tot nu toe worden uitgedrukt in de boeken die het sterk beïnvloed heeft. Tijdens het lezen van Montaigne&amp;rsquo;s Essays kwam ik tot de vaststelling dat ook Michel de onderwerpen van zijn &amp;lsquo;Essais&amp;rsquo; laat afhangen van de voorgaande werken die hij onder ogen heeft gekregen, zoals Cicero en Seneca in deel I. Iedereen moet immers zijn inspiratie ergens vandaan halen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take your time.</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/take-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/take-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to keep silent for a minute and enjoy the complete absence of traffic noise!&amp;rdquo; I yelled to my friends. We were standing on a sandy hill in the middle of national park &amp;ldquo;Hoge Veluwe&amp;rdquo;. One of our friends, a biologist, enticed us to help him identify animal tracks in the sand. I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about even-toed ungulates, but I know a bit about the joy of discovery.  &amp;ldquo;Great idea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 in books</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/2017-in-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/2017-in-books/</guid>
      <description>Goodreads presented me with a neat overview on my read books in 2017 you can also take a look at. The dull page statistics are of no interest to me, but the kind of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read do tell a story that might be worth sharing.
When it comes to keeping track of what I read, Goodreads might be the best thing that happened to me yet. But I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I&amp;rsquo;m a consequent user of my own listage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journaling in practice</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/journaling-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/journaling-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why you should journal in the first place, then maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to start reading here and here.
There are hundreds of resources available on the Internet on how to journal, how to keep a bullet journal, how to index everything, how to getting things done and so forth. The following advice is something that works for me - it might not work for you at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing creative scars</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/healing-creative-scars/</guid>
      <description>Want to skip to the practical part?
Are you aware of your problems? Once upon a time in a land not very far away (in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the very same we live in), a small boy and his Gameboy grew up. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many hobbies: gaming. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have many friends. Playing outside is okay as long as the 4 AA batteries are fully charged and the sun isn&amp;rsquo;t shining too bright and the playing is confined to one square meter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending your day with happy thoughts</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/can-i-haz-happy-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>https://brainbaking.com/post/can-i-haz-happy-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Past new year, I stopped promising silly things to myself. “This year, I’ll for sure go jogging several times a week!” — or “This year, I’ll really get into learning another language!”. We all know how these things go. Not that I made something up on the very day, these ideas are usually carefully crafted in my sketchbook and are lingering there to be exposed and finally executed.  Originally posted on Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>