<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thesamurai on Brain Baking</title>
    <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/thesamurai/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thesamurai on Brain Baking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://www.brainbaking.com/tags/thesamurai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>thesamurai</title>
      <link>http://www.brainbaking.com/wiki/games/wizardry8/thesamurai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>wouter.groeneveld@gmail.com (Wouter Groeneveld)</author>
      <guid>http://www.brainbaking.com/wiki/games/wizardry8/thesamurai/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HTML&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style######&#34;float: right;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src&#34;../../games/Wizardry8/samurai.gif&#34; style=&#34;border: none;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/HTML&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;wizardry-8-class-the-samurai&#34;&gt;Wizardry 8 Class: the Samurai&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Race&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;em&gt;Hobbit&lt;/em&gt;: best bonus points; good DEX &amp;amp; SEN
&lt;em&gt;Felpurr&lt;/em&gt;: Best SPE, fairly good DEX &amp;amp; SEN
&lt;em&gt;Mook&lt;/em&gt;: High SEN, DEX. &amp;amp; can wield Gaints Sword; KO 30%!!! (2handled) But Very low SPE.
&lt;em&gt;Dracon&lt;/em&gt;: Very good DEX, STR, and Ok SPE. Bonus VIT. Warning: very low SEN!
&lt;strong&gt;Controlling attriubutes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strength (best attrib for adding Attack Rating &amp;amp; to Hit points. Also adds damage, second controlling attrib for many skills)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dexterity (controlling attrib for many skills, very good Hit &amp;amp; AR + extra attacks / round &amp;gt;&amp;gt; critical kills++)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed (Initiative - which is not needed -, +AC - which is not needed but handy -, extra attacks - which is VERY needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senses (half AR &amp;amp; &lt;span class=&#34;wikiword&#34;&gt;ToHit&lt;/span&gt; of STR, Controlling attrib for Critical Strike which is what the sammy is quite all about)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence (if you want to cast wizardry spells, and want to do it good.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ry to maximize STR and eventually INT for the power skills. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to keep SEN over 80 (second controlling for dual plus it only adds half of the points into hit, AR as STR or even DEX does.)&amp;hellip; Altough it is wise to keep on bumping points into dexterity because it is a controlling attribute for both close combat, your sword skill AND dual weapons!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HTML&gt;
&lt;div style######&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img title&#34;The sammy&#34; src######&#34;../../games/Wizardry8/samuraiInv.jpg&#34; alt&#34;The sammy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Samurai Inventory Window&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/HTML&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlling Skills:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual weapons (you&amp;rsquo;ll want to hit as many and as often as possible for %kill percentages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criticall strike (see above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sword (25% bonus, muramasa blade has 15% kill factor and is samurai only. The ultimate weapon. Some nice off-hand things too, also daggers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close combat -obviously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wizardry when reached lvl5 - try to get power cast because it really helps to weaken enemy resistances&amp;hellip;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to work with staffs (some powerfull Bo&amp;rsquo;s are only usable by samurai &amp;amp; monks), ignore dual weapons and ignore sword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a samurai to be effective, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely want to hit as often as possible to instant kill as often as possible. So: use dual swords (highest kill rate), pump dex &amp;amp; spe for #hits, pump sen, int and str secondly for damage, hit e.d. and your magic powers (if the enemy is out of reach). I stronly disencourage any use of ranged weapons - just use your spells if you can&amp;rsquo;t reach an enemy! If you really want, you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; use a bow (high dex + sen anyway). You can also ignore his magic skills and boost STR some more, but that way you&amp;rsquo;re better off with a regular fighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About lightning strike special skill: I do have this feeling, though, that Lightning Strike just MIGHT be dependant on the amount of weight your Samurai is carrying. No, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean whether or not your Samura&amp;rsquo;s carrying load is over the top. I mean, for example, Samurai might Lightning Strike more often if, say, they&amp;rsquo;re carrying only 20% or less of their maximum Carrying Capacity. The reason why I think this may be is because I noticed that I get A LOT more Lightning Strikes in the beginning of the game. The ONLY things different during the beginning are 1)&amp;ndash;The enemies are of lower level, and 2)&amp;ndash;You&amp;rsquo;re only carrying about 25lbs or so with your Samurai.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>